Guide to the Billie Carr political papers, 1956-2003 MS 373
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III. Texas Democrats, 1971-2000, 2.5 linear ft., 5 boxes
  - Subseries B: General Correspondence, 1971-2000; 0.75 linear feet, 1.2 boxes
    - State Outgoing (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - 1971 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - 1972 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - 1974 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - 1975 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1976 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1977 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1982 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 1983-84 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1985-86 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - 1990-94 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 1996 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - 1998-2002 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Subseries C: Subject Files, 1974-2000; 1.5 linear ft., 3 boxes
    - Addresses – State of Texas (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - AFL-CIO (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - AFSCME Newsletters [American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees}; 1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - "An Action Strategy for the Rebuilding of the Texas Democrats" [by Billie Carr; pre-1980] (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Application for meetings (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Attendance Sheets – Texas Democrats; 1975 and undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Billie Carr Birthday Bash – June 1975 ('Review for 1978') (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Billie Carr Expense Fund (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Black Caucus Information (early 1980s) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Brazoria Women's Club (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 1976 Campaign Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Candidates and Nominees in May and November 1978 elections (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Challenge to the Texas Delegate Selection Plan for 1976 and the Presidential Primary Bill (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Computer Info. Secretary of State; 1980 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - County Chairs of Texas Democratic Party, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Cumulative Report; May 3, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Dallas County Democratic Executive Committee, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Delegate candidates in Senatorial Districts for Democratic Primary; March 1976 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Delegate Selection; 1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - 1974 Delegates to County Conventions – Numerical List (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Delegates to National Convention (no date) (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Democratic Party of Texas Precinct Convention Minutes; May 1, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Democratic Party Precinct Manual; March 1982 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - 2000 Democratic Party Primary Official Canvass Report; March 14, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - District 15 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Lloyd Doggett File (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Fiscal Notes; May, July 1978 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Forms for Democratic Party of Texas District Convention Minutes (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Get-Out-the-Vote [GOTV]; October 1976 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Goals and Election Goals; 1982 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Handbook for Volunteer Deputy Registrars; 1978 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Jim Hightower (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Bill Hobby (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Inaugural Invitation Lists [Carter-Mondale, 1976 Presidential election] (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Input Sheet (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Invitation Names (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Issues – State (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Letter 1982 September Convention (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Letters from John Hill; March 1978 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Letters from Slagle; 1982 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Gary Mauro, Texas Land Commissioner; 1982 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Members of State Democratic Committee and National Committee Members (no date) (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Newsletter [Texas State Employees Union]; 1982 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Open Party Caucus; August 17, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Party Platform; 1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Personal Letter Samples (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Petition Forms (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Precinct Convention Minutes, Democratic Primary Election, May 6, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "A Program for Texas Democrats" [by Billie Carr and Ed Cogburn] (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Progressive Democratic Coalition – Open Caucus, Attendance Sheets; September 25, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Republican Presidential Delegate Candidates in 1976 Primary (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Resolutions (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Resolutions Adopted by the 1978 Democratic State Convention (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Rules of the Democratic Party of Texas; February 1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Rules of the Democratic Party of Texas; March 1978 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Rules of the Democratic Party of Texas; January 1980 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Secretary of State Register [Texas Register]; November 1981 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Senate District Goals; 1982 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Bob Slagle; 1981-82 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Bob Slagle Memorandum (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Solar Energy Proposal [c. 1977] (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - State Convention (1978) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - State Democratic Party Convention – Mexican-American Democrats; 1976 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - State Election Code (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - State Files material (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - State Senate District 1 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - State Senate District 2 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - State Sixty-Sixth Legislature, Roster; 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Statement of Comptroller Bob Bullock in Response to the Travis County Grand Jury Report (1978) (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Statewide and Multi-County Races; June 1982 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - State-wide Delegates and Delegate Candidates, 1976 Election (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Texas AFL-CIO; 1977, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - "Texas Conventions: Past, Present, Future" (by Billie Carr) (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Texas Delegate Selection Plan for 1978 Democratic Nat'l. Party Conference (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Texas Dem Poll [pre-1980] (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Texas Democratic Convention, June 9-10, 2000 [includes salute to Billie Carr] (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Texas Democratic County Chairmen (no date) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Texas Democratic Open Convention Proposal; 1978 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Texas Democratic Party Clubs 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Texas Democratic Party National Delegate Selection Plan for 1984 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Texas Democratic Party National Delegate Selection Plan for 2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Texas Democratic Party Participation Program; February 1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Texas Democratic Party Rules Amendments; 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Texas Democratic Party Stationery (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Texas Democratic Party's Delegate Selection Plan for 1980 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Texas Democrats (Progressive Mod-Pro) Sign-in Sheets; 1977-78 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Texas Democrats Senate Caucus Report Forms (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Texas Democrats Steering Committee (no date) (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Texas Dems Financial Information; March 10, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Texas Dems Incoming; 1982 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Texas Dems Issues (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Texas Dems Outgoing; 1982 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Texas Dems Statement of Revenues and Expenditures; September-November, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Texas Dems Straw Polls; February 28, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Texas Federation of Democratic Women; 1983 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Texas Humanist; November/December 1982 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Texas Media Guide; 1982 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Texas State Democratic Committee, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Texas State Democratic Convention; Austin, September 17, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Texas State Democratic Convention; September 17-18, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Texas State Employees Union (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Texas State Get-Out-the Vote Program (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - TX DEM RALLY – Mar. 4 [1978] (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - U.S. Senator John Tower of Texas (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Uncommitted Caucus – Presidential election, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Unofficial Ballot – General Election; June 29, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Women's Caucus; 1982 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - "A Working Democratic Team Right for Texas," 1978 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Young Democrats; July 1982 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Young Democrats Report (Box 15, Folder 37)
- Series IV. Democratic National Committee, 1972-2000, 1.8 linear ft., 2.8 boxes.
  - Subseries A. Democratic National Committee Correspondence, 1972-2000; 1.25 linear ft., 2.5 boxes
    - Sub-subseries 1: Chronological correspondence, 1971-2000
      - 1972-73 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - 1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - 1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - 1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - 1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - 1978 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - 1979 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - 1980 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - 1981 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - 1982 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - 1983-84 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - 1985-86 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - 1992-96 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - 1997 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - 1998 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - 1999 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - 2000 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Undated. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Correspondence by name or organization, 1976-1998
      - Amendments, 1982 Democratic National Party Conference (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Billie Carr – DNC File; 1982-83 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Billie Carr – DNC Incoming; 1980-82 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Billie Carr – DNC Incoming; 1983 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Billie Carr – DNC Outgoing; c. 1978-1984 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Billie Carr, Letterhead stationery, Democratic National Committee (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Billie Carr – Democratic National Committee; 1988-89 [Removed from binder] (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Billie Carr Reports... (September 1982) (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Democratic National Committee Fall Meeting – 1997 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Democratic Party Charter and By-Laws; 1976 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Democratic Party Conference, Philadelphia; June 1982 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - DNC Commission on Presidential Nominations, Membership List (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - DNC Executive Committee, 1997-98 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - DNC Women's Caucus; October 8, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Hunt Commission Report [Commission on Presidential Nomination] (1982?) (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - National Directory of Women Elected Officials, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - NDC Liberal Caucus – Attendance Files; 1982-83 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Report of the Commission on Presidential Nomination; 1982 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Statements to Hunt Commission (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Democratic National Conventions, 1976-2000
    - 1976 (New York City) (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 1980 (New York City) (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 1984 (San Francisco) (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - 1988 (Atlanta) (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - 1992 (New York City) (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - 1996 (Chicago) (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - 2000 (Los Angeles) (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Current Work [Democratic National Convention, August 2000] (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Series V. New Democratic Coalition, 1973-84, 2 linear inches
  - Correspondence, 1973-77 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1979-83 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - National New Democratic Coalition, Correspondence, 1975-84 (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Series VI. Billie Carr Associates, 1976-1995, .5 linear ft.,1 box
  - Billie Carr Associates (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - BC A Computer Information (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - BC A Incoming correspondence (1982-83) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - BC A Tapes (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Campaign Company (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Candidates Campaign Info. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Competitors of BC A (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1976-79 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - List of Liberals or Progressives (1980) (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Mail out bids (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Files (1981-82 and undated) (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell Group, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Orders, forms (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Precincts with opposition (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Sample Mail (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Statements for work done (1982-83) (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Sworn Statements (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Unofficial Ballot – Bob Hauge (1982) (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - 1982 Voter's Guide on Women's Issues (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Billie Carr's Political Directory (removed from binder); 1986 and undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Billie Carr's Political Directory (removed from binder); 1994-95 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Series VII. Memorabilia, 1950s-2002, 2 linear ft., 4 boxes.
  - Subseries A: Invitations, 1960s-2002
    - Presidential Inauguration (Clinton/Gore), 1993 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Presidential Inauguration (Clinton/Gore), 1997 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Invitations, 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Invitations – 1980-84 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Invitations – 1985-87 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Invitations – 1993-96 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Invitations – 1997-99 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Invitations – 2000-02 and partial dates (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Cards, n.d.
    - Presidents and Vice Presidents (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Governors and Congressmen (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Democratic National Committee (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - General (Box 21, Folder 4-6)
  - Subseries C: Photos
    - Photos from scrapbook (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Presidential, Vice Presidential (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Photos – General (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
    - 3 compact discs of scanned photos, originals of which have been retained by Billie Carr's family (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Subseries D. Memorabilia, n.d.
    - Name badges, political pins, posters, bumperstickers (Box 22)
    - Oversize photos, Awards and plaques (Box 23)